Andrew Chew . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate from the University of Toronto with a background in software development, data analytics, and have over 5 years of customer service experience. I am highly adaptive to new environments and always looking for opportunities to enhance my capabilities. Currently, I am working as a Junior Software and Data Engineer at Jarvis Consulting Group where I work with my team in an agile environment to deliver high quality software products. I believe that the software industry is moving at a incredibly rapid pace with new innovations and technologies being discovered every day. I am excited to pursue my two biggest passions in software and data engineering to join this ever evolving community, utilizing big data to design products to make the world a better and infinitely more interesting place.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git/GitHub, R/R Markdown, Microsoft Office Suite

Competent: Docker, Python, GitFlow, LateX, Google Workspace

Familiar: VNC, Google Cloud Platform, JavaFX, C, Verilog

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_AndrewChew

Linux Cluster Monitoring Agent [GitHub]: Developed a Linux Cluster Monitoring Agent allowing the Jarvis Linux Cluster Administration team to obtain server hardware and usage statistics in real time. Provisioned a psql instance using a docker container to persist data and designed a bash agent to be installed on servers to collect and insert data into the database. Implemented 3 SQL queries to answer business questions. Collaborated with the development team using the Agile workflow.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

Twitter App: Not StartedJDBC App: Not StartedGrep App: Not Started

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not StartedSpark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

Highlighted Projects

Sokoban, Othello, and Tenner Grid AI Solver: Applied key concepts in AI to develop solvers for 3 games using python attaining a final grade of 94. Strategized and developed heuristics to improve runtime performance of solvers by over 75%.

Data Visualization Project on Climate Change [GitHub]: Managed a team of 3 to indentify and analyze 4 large datasets, investigating the relationship between emissions and methods of transportation. Led tutorial sessions introducting RStudio and Version Control via GitHub integration to facilitate collaboration between team members. Designed 3 interactive data visualizations using psychological principles to effectively present and communicate key findings. Rapidly learned and applied the Shiny R package within a week to deliver infographic publicly by deploying a Shiny App online.

Cross-Stitch Image Processing Project: Developed an R program to produce a cross-stitch pattern from an image using k-means clustering attaining a final grade of 88. Compiled a self-contained non-technical pdf document using Rmd demonstrating the process of the program and how to use it.

Twitter Sentiment during COVID-19 Project: Scraped over 4 million tweets to build a dataset to analyze consumer sentiment during the pandemic in a team of 4. Performed data analysis to identify new terms relating to the pandemic and how they relate to consumer sentiment using machine learning techniques in python.

Restaurant POS System Project: Managed a team of 3 to fully develop a restaurant point of sale system in java utilizing fundamental OOP concepts. Built a fully functioning GUI using JavaFX. Effectively identified and fixed core issues in the code base using vigorous unit testing to improve user experience.

Professional Experiences

Junior Software & Data Engineer, Jarvis Consulting Group (2021-present): Develop software using the SDLC process in an agile work environment, delivering high-quality products.

Produce Clerk Part-Time, Loblaw Companies Limited (2016-present): Advise customers on over 400 products leading to improved customer satisfaction. Effectively handle conflict resolution in a sensitive and professional manner ensuring safety in the workplace. Train new employees for day-to-day operations. Successfully completed diversity training.

Events Coordinator, Hope United Church (2012-2016): Managed a team of 3 to organize after-school activities for 10 children. Strategized learning sessions for grade school children in Mathematics and Science. Taught children basic piano skills.

Education

University of Toronto (2017-2021), Honours Bachelor of Science, Actuarial Science, Statistics, and Computer Science - President's Entrance Scholarship - Samuel Eckler Memorial Scholarship in Actuarial Science - GPA: 3.31/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Coursera Data Scientist Toolbox (2020)
- Coursera R Programming (2020)
- Pianist
- Ultimate Frisbee Player
- Nature Enthusiast